Sajad Jalilian

Backend Developer

| +98 9375515339 | sajadjalilian88 [at] gmail [dot] com |

| linkedin.com/in/sajadjalilian | sajadjalilian.github.io |

About Me

I'm an old-time geek! I love programming and creating web applications. I Try to write code for humans, machines eventually will understand it anyway! I believe in minimalism in life and code, Less is better.

I'm interested in the whole web application development life cycle; from small apps with a handful of users to hundreds of microservices with millions of users. Engineering, designing, and implementing them just excites me.

Skills & Endorsements

General Software Development

Design Patterns - SOLID/KISS/YAGNI - Microservices - RESTful WebServices - MVC

DotNet Ecosystem and tools

C# - ASP.NET - Entity Framework - MediatR - MassTransit - HangFire - Ocelot - FluentValidation amd more...

Tools I work with

 $\label{linux-Version} Linux-Version Control(Git)-Containerization(Docker)-SQL-RDBMS(PostgreSQL-SQL Server-MySQL)-ORM-In-Memory cache(Redis)-Message-Bus-Message-Broker-Logging(Graylog-Sentry)-Task scheduling(BackgroundService)-CI/CD(GitHub-GitLab-Azure DevOps)$

I also worked with

Python - Django/DRF - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Non-Technical

Soft-skill and being good with people - Agile Methodologies - Critical thinking

Experience

DotNet Backend Developer

BlueBitSoft / Jul 2021 - Present

We use microservices to integrate all parts of the company systems together and stay agile at the same time.

Our team is responsible for several microservices. We develop CMS for the company and our subset pharmacies in the Netherlands and Germany. We help them manage all sorts of content around medicine and health care. A client report is another service we work on, patients can follow the prescriptions from the start of the process in the pharmacy until delivery at their home or other pickup stations. We also provide raw data for BI Specialists to do magic on it; we send daily reports to pharmacies; etc...

DotNet Backend Developer

Paaydar Smart Network/ Apr 2021 - Jun 2021

I was working on internal financial systems. Our system handled thousands of sales daily and calculated profits, commissions, etc...

Python Backend Developer

Arsh / Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

I worked on the Iranian calendar service for business, during my work we added several planning features for admins and users, like setting meetings and adding participants, sharing meeting notes and plans, recurring meetings, etc...

Arsh / Sep 2020 - Jan 2021

I was in charge of refactoring and migrating the internal HR system from Python version 2 to 3, Django 1.11 to the latest and preparing for the next LTS version. Python 3 had significant breaking changes, we had to refactor the majority of the code-base to migrate to python 3.

Education

The University of Applied Science and Technology Kermanshah Associate Computer Hardware Engineering / 2010 - 2012

Projects

Hamporsesh

Clean Survey app using "Onion Architecture" DotNet/ASP.NET and C#

Language

English ●●●○